In the first case, the number of signed in users is
在第一个案例中 登录用户量
definitely a good population sizing metric.
无疑非常适合作为总体规模指标
Since the unit of diversion is the user-id, the signed in users are being
由于分组单元为用户 ID
randomly assigned to the experiment and control groups.
登录用户可随机分配给实验组和对照组
So, you should definitely have roughly the same number of users in each group.
这样 从各组获取的用户量肯定就大致相同
Now, number of cookies and number of events are a little more tricky.
但是 cookies 数量或事件数量就比较棘手
They're not being directly randomized.
因为它们不能直接随机化
But, they should still be split evenly between the two groups.
但最后需要在两组间平均分配
Unless users in the experiment tend to clear their cookies more often, or
除非用户经常清理 cookies
visit fewer pages, or something like that.
或更少访问页面 诸如此类
If that's happening,it's probably not a good thing, and
如果发生了以上情况 你肯定想了解它
it's definitely something you want to know about.
因为这可能不是好现象
So, these are also good population sizing invariants.
所以它们也可以作为总体规模的不变量
The click-through rate on the Start Now button is a good invariant metric.
现在开始按钮的点击率也可以作为较好的不变量指标
Since users click the Start Now button before they see the course
因为用户先要点击”现在开始”按钮 然后才能浏览课程表
list, the click-through rate on the Start Now button shouldn't be
所以此按钮的点击率
affected by this change.
不应受变更的影响
The time taken to complete a course, on the other hand,
但是 另一方面
could be affected by this change.
完成课程的平均时间却会受其影响
If ordering the courses differently does cause users to enroll in different
如果对课程重新排序 确实会对报班课程产生影响
courses, then that could change how long it takes users to complete the courses
那么用户完成所报课程的时间
they do enroll in.
也会发生变化
For example, maybe putting easier courses first causes more users to start
例如 如果把较为简单的课程放在前面
with easier courses, and then they finish them faster.
那么更多用户会选择这类课程 而且完成时间也更短
So, this would not be a good invariant.
因此不适合作为不变量
In the second case, again,
与第一个案例相同
the first three metrics will all be good population sizing invariants.
第二个案例中 前三个指标也是很好的总体规模不变量指标
Number of events is good since this is the unit of diversion.
事件数量 作为分组单元 是不错的指标
So, this is being randomly assigned between the experiment and
它可以在实验组和对照组中
control groups.
随机分配
Signed in users and cookies are both larger than the unit of diversion,
登录用户量和 cookies 数量都比分组单元大
in the sense that one user or one cookie could correspond to multiple events.
也就是说 一名用户或一条 cookie 可能对应多个事件
So, since the events are being randomly assigned, the number of signed in users
鉴于事件分配的随机性
and cookies shouldn't be different between the two groups either.
两组的登录用户量和 cookies 数量也不应有所差别
The click-through rate of the Start Now button would be a good invariant metric,
因为用户点击“现在开始”按钮后才能观看视频
since users click Start Now before viewing any videos.
所以该按钮的点击率适合作为不变量指标
There could be a learning effect, but
也可以采用学习效应
you won't catch learning effects if you're diverting by event anyway.
但如果你通过事件进行分组 你也无法发现学习效应
The time to get through a class can't be tracked if you're using
并且 如果以事件为分组单元
event-based diversion.
则无法追踪完成课程所需的时间
Since by the time the user gets through a course, they could have been
这是因为在完成某一课程的学习时
assigned to both the experiment and the control group multiple times.
用户可能曾多次被分配至实验组和对照组
Even if you could track this, it wouldn't be a good invariant,
而且 由于加载时间会影响课程的完成时间
since load time could affect how long it takes to complete a class.
所以即便可以追踪 它也不适合作为不变量
For example, users could switch tabs if videos load slowly, and
例如 如果视频加载速度太慢 用户会切换至其它标签页
end up getting distracted, and taking longer to complete the course.
最后注意力分散 花费更长时间完成学习